<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<facts>
    <fact>Banging your head against a wall burns 150 calories an hour.</fact>
    <fact>In the UK, it is illegal to eat mince pies on Christmas Day!</fact>
    <fact>Pteronophobia is the fear of being tickled by feathers!</fact>
    <fact>When hippos are upset, their sweat turns red.</fact>
    <fact>A flock of crows is known as a murder.</fact>
    <fact>"Facebook Addiction Disorder" is a mental disorder identified by Psychologists.</fact>
    <fact>The average woman uses her height in lipstick every 5 years.</fact>
    <fact>29th May is officially “Put a Pillow on Your Fridge Day“.</fact>
    <fact>Cherophobia is the fear of fun.</fact>
    <fact>Human saliva has a boiling point three times that of regular water.</fact>
    <fact>If you lift a kangaroo’s tail off the ground it can’t hop.</fact>
    <fact>Hyphephilia are people who get aroused by touching fabrics.</fact>
    <fact>Billy goats urinate on their own heads to smell more attractive to females.</fact>
    <fact>The person who invented the Frisbee was cremated and made into frisbees after he died!</fact>
    <fact>During your lifetime, you will produce enough saliva to fill two swimming pools.</fact>
    <fact>An eagle can kill a young deer and fly away with it.</fact>
    <fact>Polar bears can eat as many as 86 penguins in a single sitting.</fact>
    <fact>King Henry VIII slept with a gigantic axe beside him.</fact>
    <fact>Bikinis and tampons invented by men.</fact>
    <fact>If Pinokio says "My Noes Will Grow Now", it would cause a paradox.</fact>
    <fact>Heart attacks are more likely to happen on a Monday.</fact>
    <fact>If you consistently fart for 6 years and 9 months, enough gas is produced to create the energy of an atomic bomb!</fact>
    <fact>An average person’s yearly fast food intake will contain 12 pubic hairs.</fact>
    <fact>The top six foods that make your fart are beans, corn, bell peppers, cauliflower, cabbage and milk</fact>
    <fact>There is a species of spider called the Hobo Spider.</fact>
    <fact>‘Penis Fencing’ is a scientific term for the mating ritual between flatworms. It involves two flatworms attempting to stab the other flatworm with their penis.</fact>
    <fact>A toaster uses almost half as much energy as a full-sized oven.</fact>
    <fact>A baby spider is called a spiderling.</fact>
    <fact>You cannot snore and dream at the same time.</fact>
    <fact>The following can be read forward and backwards: Do geese see God?</fact>
    <fact>A baby octopus is about the size of a flea when it is born</fact>
    <fact>A sheep, a duck and a rooster were the first passengers in a hot air balloon. </fact>
    <fact>In Uganda, 50% of the population is under 15 years of age.</fact>
    <fact>Hitler’s mother considered abortion but the doctor persuaded her to keep the baby.</fact>
    <fact>Arab women can initiate a divorce if their husbands don’t pour coffee for them.</fact>
    <fact>Recycling one glass jar saves enough energy to watch TV for 3 hours.Smearing a small amount of dog feces on an insect bite will relieve the itching and swelling.</fact>
    <fact>Smearing a small amount of dog feces on an insect bite will relieve the itching and swelling.</fact>
    <fact>Catfish are the only animals that naturally have an odd number of whiskers.</fact>
    <fact>Facebook, Skype and Twitter are all banned in China.</fact>
    <fact>95% of people text things they could never say in person.</fact>
    <fact>The Titanic was the first ship to use the SOS signal.</fact>
    <fact>In Poole, ‘Pound World’ went out of business because of a store across the road called ’99p Stores’, which was selling the same products but for just 1 pence cheaper!</fact>
    <fact>About 8,000 Americans are injured by musical instruments each year.</fact>
    <fact>The French language has seventeen different words for ‘surrender’.</fact>
    <fact>Nearly three percent of the ice in Antarctic glaciers is penguin urine.</fact>
    <fact>Bob Dylan’s real name is Robert Zimmerman.</fact>
    <fact>A crocodile can’t poke its tongue out</fact>
    <fact>Sea otters hold hands when they sleep so they don’t drift away from each other.</fact>
    <fact>A small child could swim through the veins of a blue whale.</fact>
    <fact>Bin Laden’s death was announced on 1st May 2011. Hitler’s death was announced on 1st May 1945.</fact>
    <fact>J.K. Rowling chose the unusual name ‘Hermione’ so young girls wouldn’t be teased for being nerdy!</fact>
    <fact>Hewlett-Packard’s name was decided in a coin toss.</fact>
    <fact>The total number of steps in the Eiffel Tower are 1665.</fact>
    <fact>The Pokémon Hitmonlee and Hitmonchan are based off of Bruce Lee and Jackie Chan.</fact>
    <fact>The toothpaste ‘Colgate’ in Spanish translates to ‘go hang yourself’.</fact>
    <fact>Pirates wore earrings because they believed it improved their eyesight.</fact>
    <fact>Los Angeles’s full name is “El Pueblo de Nuestra Senora la Reina de los Angeles de Porciuncula.”</fact>
    <fact>Dr. Kellogg introduced Kellogg Corn Flakes in hopes that it would reduce masturbation.</fact>
    <fact>The testicles on an octopus are located in its head!</fact>
    <fact>In England, in the 1880’s, “Pants” was considered a dirty word.</fact>
    <fact>It snowed in the Sahara desert for 30 minutes on the 18th February 1979.</fact>
    <fact>Every human spent about half an hour as a single cell.</fact>
    <fact>If you leave everything to the last minute… it will only take a minute.</fact>
    <fact>Ithyphallophobia is the fear of erections.</fact>
    <fact>The first alarm clock could only ring at 4am.</fact>
    <fact>Birds don’t urinate.</fact>
    <fact>Dying is illegal in the Houses of Parliaments – This has been voted as the most ridiculous law by the British citizens.</fact>
    <fact>The word ‘ejaculation’ comes from the Latin word meaning ‘throwing out’.</fact>
    <fact>The 20th of March is known as Snowman Burning Day!</fact>
    <fact>Slugs have 4 noses.</fact>
    <fact>Panphobia is the fear of everything… which is a pretty unlucky phobia to have.</fact>
    <fact>An apple, potato, and onion all taste the same if you eat them with your nose plugged.</fact>
    <fact>George Washington grew marijuana in his garden.</fact>
    <fact>A company in Taiwan makes dinnerware out of wheat, so you can eat your plate!</fact>
    <fact>The average person walks the equivalent of twice around the world in a lifetime.</fact>
    <fact>The Bible is the most shoplifted book in the world.</fact>
    <fact>Marco Hort has the world record for fitting 264 straws in his mouth at once!</fact>
    <fact>Mel Blanc – the voice of Bugs Bunny – was allergic to carrots.</fact>
    <fact>California has issued 6 drivers licenses to people named Jesus Christ.</fact>
    <fact>According to Genesis 1:20-22 the chicken came before the egg.</fact>
    <fact>In the Caribbean there are oysters that can climb trees.</fact>
    <fact>Worms eat their own poo.</fact>
    <fact>Squirrels forget where they hide about half of their nuts.</fact>
    <fact>Over 1000 birds a year die from smashing into windows.</fact>
    <fact>The inventor of the Waffle Iron did not like waffles.</fact>
    <fact>George W. Bush was once a cheerleader.</fact>
    <fact>In Japan, it is completely acceptable to name your child ‘Buttocks’ or ‘Prostitute’.</fact>
    <fact>In 1895 Hampshire police handed out the first ever speeding ticket, fining a man for doing 6mph!</fact>
    <fact>Each year, there are more than 40,000 toilet related injuries in the United States.</fact>
    <fact>A tapir has the largest penis-to-body ratio of any animal.</fact>
    <fact>Mewtwo is a clone of the Pokémon Mew, yet it comes before Mew in the Pokédex.</fact>
    <fact>Every year more than 2500 left-handed people are killed from using right-handed products.</fact>
    <fact>Madonna suffers from garophobia which is the fear of thunder.</fact>
    <fact>China has more English speakers than the United States.</fact>
    <fact>Samuel L. Jackson requested to have a purple light saber in Star Wars in order for him to accept the part as Mace Windu.</fact>
    <fact>Paraskavedekatriaphobia is the fear of Friday the 13th!</fact>
    <fact>Kleenex tissues were originally used as filters in gas masks.</fact>
    <fact>Upon losing battles, apes will tend to masturbate.</fact>
    <fact>Ronald McDonald is “Donald McDonald” in Japan because it makes pronunciation easier for the Japanese. In Singapore he’s known as “Uncle McDonald”.</fact>
    <fact>In the average lifetime, a person will walk the equivalent of 5 times around the equator.</fact>
    <fact>Odontophobia is the fear of teeth.</fact>
    <fact>The 57 on Heinz ketchup bottles represents the number of varieties of pickles the company once had.</fact>
    <fact>The surface area of an average-sized brick is 79 cm squared.</fact>
    <fact>According to suicide statistics, Monday is the favored day for self-destruction.</fact>
    <fact>Cats sleep 16 to 18 hours per day.</fact>
    <fact>The most common name in the world is Mohammed.</fact>
    <fact>Karoke means "empty orchestra" in Japanese.</fact>
    <fact>The first known contraceptive was crocodile dung, used by Egyptians in 2000 B.C.</fact>
    <fact>When you die your hair still grows for a couple of months.</fact>
    <fact>There are two credit cards for every person in the United States.</fact>
    <fact>Isaac Asimov is the only author to have a book in every Dewey-decimal category.</fact>
    <fact>The newspaper serving Frostbite Falls, Minnesota, the home of Rocky and Bullwinkle, is the Picayune Intellegence.</fact>
    <fact>The most money ever paid for a cow in an auction was $1.3 million.</fact>
    <fact>It took Leo Tolstoy six years to write "War and Peace".</fact>
    <fact>The Neanderthal's brain was bigger than yours is.</fact>
    <fact>On the new hundred dollar bill the time on the clock tower of Independence Hall is 4:10.</fact>
    <fact>The pancreas produces Insulin.</fact>
    <fact>1 in 5,000 north Atlantic lobsters are born bright blue.</fact>
    <fact>There are 10 human body parts that are only 3 letters long (eye hip arm leg ear toe jaw rib lip gum).</fact>
    <fact>A skunk's smell can be detected by a human a mile away.</fact>
    <fact>The word "lethologica" describes the state of not being able to remember the word you want.</fact>
    <fact>The king of hearts is the only king without a moustache.</fact>
    <fact>Henry Ford produced the model T only in black because the black paint available at the time was the fastest to dry.</fact>
    <fact>The three best-known western names in China: Jesus Christ, Richard Nixon, and Elvis Presley.</fact>
    <fact>Every year about 98% of the atoms in your body are replaced.</fact>
    <fact>Elephants are the only mammals that can't jump.</fact>
    <fact>The international telephone dialing code for Antarctica is 672.</fact>
    <fact>World Tourist day is observed on September 27.</fact>
    <fact>Women are 37% more likely to go to a psychiatrist than men are.</fact>
    <fact>The human heart creates enough pressure to squirt blood 30 feet (9 m).</fact>
    <fact>Diet Coke was only invented in 1982.</fact>
    <fact>There are more than 1,700 references to gems and precious stones in the King James translation of the Bible.</fact>
    <fact>When snakes are born with two heads, they fight each other for food.</fact>
    <fact>American car horns beep in the tone of F.</fact>
    <fact>There are twice as many kangaroos in Australia as there are people. The kangaroo population is estimated at about 40 million.</fact>
    <fact>Police dogs are trained to react to commands in a foreign language; commonly German but more recently Hungarian.</fact>
    <fact>The Australian $5 to $100 notes are made of plastic.</fact>
    <fact>St. Stephen is the patron saint of bricklayers.</fact>
    <fact>The average person makes about 1,140 telephone calls each year.</fact>
    <fact>Stressed is Desserts spelled backwards.</fact>
    <fact>If you had enough water to fill one million goldfish bowls, you could fill an entire stadium.</fact>
    <fact>Mary Stuart became Queen of Scotland when she was only six days old.</fact>
    <fact>Charlie Brown's father was a barber.</fact>
    <fact>Flying from London to New York by Concord, due to the time zones crossed, you can arrive 2 hours before you leave.</fact>
    <fact>You burn more calories sleeping than you do watching TV.</fact>
    <fact>A lion's roar can be heard from five miles away.</fact>
    <fact>Canadian researchers have found that Einstein's brain was 15% wider than normal.</fact>
    <fact>The average person spends about 2 years on the phone in a lifetime.</fact>
    <fact>The fist product to have a bar code was Wrigleys gum.</fact>
    <fact>Beatrix Potter created the first of her legendary "Peter Rabbit" children's stories in 1902.</fact>
    <fact>In ancient Rome, it was considered a sign of leadership to be born with a crooked nose.</fact>
    <fact>The word "nerd" was first coined by Dr. Seuss in "If I Ran the Zoo."</fact>
    <fact>A 41-gun salute is the traditional salute to a royal birth in Great Britain.</fact>
    <fact>The bagpipe was originally made from the whole skin of a dead sheep.</fact>
    <fact>Revolvers cannot be silenced because of all the noisy gasses which escape the cylinder gap at the rear of the barrel.</fact>
    <fact>A car that shifts manually gets 2 miles more per gallon of gas than a car with automatic shift.</fact>
    <fact>Cats can hear ultrasound.</fact>
    <fact>Dueling is legal in Paraguay as long as both parties are registered blood donors.</fact>
    <fact>The highest point in Pennsylvania is lower than the lowest point in Colorado.</fact>
    <fact>The United States has never lost a war in which mules were used.</fact>
    <fact>Children grow faster in the springtime.</fact>
    <fact>On average, there are 178 sesame seeds on each McDonalds BigMac bun.</fact>
    <fact>Paul Revere rode on a horse that belonged to Deacon Larkin.</fact>
    <fact>The Baby Ruth candy bar was actually named after Grover Cleveland's baby daughter, Ruth.</fact>
    <fact>Minus 40 degrees Celsius is exactly the same as minus 40 degrees Fahrenheit.</fact>
    <fact>7.5 million toothpicks can be created from a cord of wood.</fact>
    <fact>The plastic things on the end of shoelaces are called aglets.</fact>
    <fact>"Goodbye" came from "God bye" which came from "God be with you."</fact>
    <fact>February is Black History Month.</fact>
    <fact>Jane Barbie was the woman who did the voice recordings for the Bell System.</fact>
    <fact>The first drive-in service station in the United States was opened by Gulf Oil Company - on December 1, 1913, in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</fact>
    <fact>The elephant is the only animal with 4 knees.</fact>
    <fact>Kansas state law requires pedestrians crossing the highways at night to wear tail lights.</fact>
    <fact>Fish cough.</fact>
    <fact>Cashews are always sold without their shells because the shell contains an oil that can cause a rash similar to poison ivy.</fact>
    <fact>When Mario made his debut in the original Donkey Kong in 1981, he was known as Jumpman.</fact>
    <fact>One of Prince Charles's Secret Service code names was "Unicorn.</fact>
    <fact>Actress Uma Thurman's father was the first known Westerner to become a Tibetan Buddhist monk.</fact>
    <fact>At more than 3.3 million square miles, the Sahara Desert is as large as the world's next 20 largest hot deserts combined.</fact>
    <fact>At launch, around 300,000 gallons of water was released beneath the Space Shuttle's engines as a noise suppressant.</fact>
    <fact>Naperville Central High School near Chicago, Illinois, is the only high school in America with an Egyptian mummy.</fact>
    <fact>A flu outbreak canceled the 1919 Stanley Cup when too many players were too ill to play past the fifth game.</fact>
    <fact>Picky linguists will tell you that the feminine version of "dude" is "dudine," not "dudette."</fact>
    <fact>The University of Minnesota is older than the state of Minnesota.</fact>
    <fact>In 1980, Detroit presented Saddam Hussein with a key to the city.</fact>
    <fact>Michael J. Fox’s middle name is Andrew.</fact>
    <fact>Julia Child was 6 feet, 2 inches tall.</fact>
    <fact>A Mercurian day is longer than its year.</fact>
    <fact>Elvis was a big fan of Monty Python and would often act out the British comedy troupe's skits in front of friends.</fact>
    <fact>Doves were called "turtles" long before today's turtles were known by that name.</fact>
    <fact>A large percentage of the budget for Monty Python and the Holy Grail was donated by members of Led Zeppelin and Pink Floyd.</fact>
    <fact>Caffeine serves the function of a pesticide in a coffee plant.</fact>
    <fact>U.S. paper money is currently produced at two facilities, one in Washington D.C. and another in Fort Worth, Texas.</fact>
    <fact>The actor who was inside R2-D2 hated the guy who played C-3PO.</fact>
    <fact>The famous Aaron Burr “Got Milk?” ad from 1993 was directed by Michael Bay.</fact>
    <fact>The longest jellyfish on record measured 160 feet, more than half the length of a football field.</fact>
    <fact>When Milton Bradley introduced Twister in 1966, critics denounced the game as "sex in a box."</fact>
    <fact>Hunger Games author Suzanne Collins also wrote for Clarissa Explains It All.</fact>
    <fact>According to a 2012 New York Times story, 1% of Americans still get on the Internet with an AOL dial-up connection.</fact>
    <fact>Symbols such as "!#@%" that are used to indicate swearing in comic strips are called grawlix.</fact>
    <fact>The Caesar Salad was not invented by the Italians, but by a restaurant owner in Tijuana, Mexico.</fact>
    <fact>The firefly is not actually a fly, but a beetle.</fact>
    <fact>Winona Ryder was cast to play Michael Corleone's daughter in Godfather III. When she dropped out, Sofia Coppola got the part.</fact>
    <fact>Overall U.S. consumption of poultry has doubled over the last 25 years, from 18 million pounds to 36 million pounds.</fact>
    <fact>The act of snapping one's fingers has a name. It is called a "fillip."</fact>
    <fact>The first registered domain name was symbolics.com. It was registered on March 15th, 1985.</fact>
    <fact>Google's founders were ready to sell to Excite for under $1 million in 1999. Excite turned them down.</fact>
    <fact>In all of Shakespeare's works, only one word starts with an "X" - Xanthippe, Socrates wife. He uses her name in The Taming of the Shrew.</fact>
    <fact>The phrase "goody two shoes" comes from a fable written in 1766 by Oliver Goldsmith about a poor little girl who could only afford one shoe.</fact>
    <fact>Marie Osmond goes by her middle name. Her actual first name is Olive.</fact>
    <fact>Dogs can experience a runner's high.</fact>
    <fact>Nebraska is the only state in the union that has a unicameral legislature.</fact>
    <fact>The Gateway Arch in St. Louis is as wide at its base as it is tall (630 feet).</fact>
    <fact>A shrimp can swim backwards.</fact>
    <fact>J.K. Rowling invented Quidditch in a pub.</fact>
    <fact>O'Hare Airport is named after Al Capone's laywer's son, Lt. Cmdr. Butch O'Hare.</fact>
    <fact>The little bump on the front side of your ear is called a tragus.</fact>
    <fact>Though it's rarely used, the word referring to half a computer byte is a "nibble."</fact>
    <fact>Albert Einstein never received a Nobel Prize for his theory of relativity.</fact>
    <fact>The peacock is actually the name of the male peafowl. The female is called a peahen.</fact>
    <fact>George Washington preferred not to shake the hands of visitors. He would bow instead.</fact>
    <fact>When business was slow in the early days of the Boeing Company, they had their woodworkers make furniture.</fact>
    <fact>Crayola means "oily chalk." The name is derived from the French words craie, or "chalk," and ola, an abbreviation for "oleaginous," or "oily."</fact>
    <fact>In 1950, Zenith created the first TV remote control, called "Lazy Bones."</fact>
    <fact>Whales still have hip bones.</fact>
    <fact>The depressed area of skin under your nose and above your upper lip is called your philtrum.</fact>
    <fact>Freddie Mercury, the lead singer of British music group Queen, was born in Zanzibar as Farrokh Bulsara.</fact>
    <fact>The British comedy show Monty Python's Flying Circus had a decidedly American theme song, John Philip Sousa's "Liberty Bell March.</fact>
    <fact>A National Weather Service study indicated that more than eight out of every ten people injured or killed by lightning were men.</fact>
    <fact>Your foot is the same size as the distance between your wrist and elbow.</fact>
    <fact>The Michelin Man has a name – Bibendum, though close friends call him simply “Bib.”</fact>
    <fact>William McKinley was on the $500 bill, Grover Cleveland was on the $1,000, and James Madison was on the $5,000.</fact>
    <fact>Only about one-fifth of the world's largest desert, the Sahara, is covered with sand; the remainder is made up of rock formations.</fact>
    <fact>Elmo is the most recognizable children’s character in the U.S.</fact>
    <fact>Henry Ford was a proponent of hiring the handicapped. In 1919, more than 20% of his workforce had some form of disability.</fact>
    <fact>There are molecules called Sonic hedgehog and Robotnikinin, both named after the popular Sega characters.</fact>
    <fact>The 1976 comedy Silent Movie by Mel Brooks has exactly one WORD of dialog, "NO!," spoken by the famous mime Marcel Marceau.</fact>
    <fact>Tuesday Island, Wednesday Island, Thursday Island, and Friday Island all exist in the Torres Strait off the coast of Australia.</fact>
    <fact>Three Men and a Baby was directed by Leonard Nimoy.</fact>
    <fact>President Gerald Ford was offered contracts with the Green Bay Packers and the Detroit Lions.</fact>
    <fact>The amazingly popular drink Guinness is not black. It is actually a very dark shade of ruby.</fact>
    <fact>The only U.S. president to have been the head of a union was Ronald Reagan, former president of the Screen Actors Guild.</fact>
    <fact>The White House was originally called the President's Palace. Theodore Roosevelt gave the White House its current name in 1901.</fact>
    <fact>Braces go all the way back to ancient Egypt. In fact, archeologists have found several mummies with crude metal bands wrapped around their teeth.</fact>
    <fact>Roy Roger's Trigger was Maid Marion's horse in the Errol Flynn version of Robin Hood.</fact>
    <fact>In early drafts of Truman Capote's Breakfast at Tiffany’s, Holly Golightly was named Connie Gustafson.</fact>
    <fact>The word "unfriend" appeared in print all the way back in 1659.</fact>
    <fact>The top three areas of coupon distribution are household cleaning products, pet foods, and frozen foods.</fact>
    <fact>To deter nativity scene theft, BrickHouse Security provides free GPS trackers that can be installed in Baby Jesus.</fact>
    <fact>Every year 0.1 percent of BB gun shootings are attempted suicides. That means about 30 people every year try to kill themselves with the tiny pellets</fact>
    <fact>The first item sold on eBay was a broken laser pointer. A collector of broken laser pointers bought it for $14.83.</fact>
    <fact>Prince Harry is partial owner of a racehorse named Usain Colt.</fact>
    <fact>Bill Cosby won three consecutive Emmy awards in 1966, 1967 and 1968 as Best Drama Actor for his role in I, Spy.</fact>
    <fact>Libra is the only zodiac sign represented by an inanimate object.</fact>
    <fact>There are roughly 70 ingredients in the McRib.</fact>
    <fact>Visit a waterfall at dusk and you may see moonbows—nighttime rainbows.</fact>
    <fact>In 1979, members of the Hatfield and McCoy families faced off once again— on the game show Family Feud.</fact>
    <fact>The highest temperature ever recorded on earth was a searing 136° F. The scorcher occurred in Al Aziziyah, Libya on September 13, 1922.</fact>
    <fact>Horses cannot breathe through their mouth. If their nostrils become obstructed, they could suffocate.</fact>
    <fact>Bill Clinton reportedly only ever sent two emails as president, one of which was a test message to see if he was doing it correctly.</fact>
    <fact>Morse Code was made for letters, not numbers. In fact, signaling the number "one" requires five dots and dashes.</fact>
    <fact>The tip of a fencing weapon is the second fastest moving object in the Olympics. The fastest is a bullet.</fact>
    <fact>In 1997, Mikhail Gorbachev appeared in a Pizza Hut commercial.</fact>
    <fact>President John Quincy Adams kept an alligator in the East Room.</fact>
    <fact>A former slave ship captain wrote the song "Amazing Grace."</fact>
    <fact>SeaWorld began as a plan by four UCLA alums to open an ocean-themed restaurant with a marine show.</fact>
    <fact>Horseradish is a member of the mustard family and can count cauliflower, kale and brussels sprouts among its cousins.</fact>
    <fact>There are 293 ways to make change for a U.S. dollar.</fact>
    <fact>Ty Cobb was baseball's first millionaire.</fact>
    <fact>The spooky theme song for Alfred Hitchcock Presents is titled "Funeral March of a Marionette."</fact>
    <fact>Shemp’s son was no Stooge. He invented the self-serve gas station.</fact>
    <fact>The second largest country by land area is Canada, after Russia.</fact>
    <fact>The term "jumbo" is taken from the name of one of P.T. Barnum's large circus elephants.</fact>
    <fact>President James Garfield could write Greek with one hand while simultaneously writing Latin with the other.</fact>
    <fact>Stan and Jan Berenstain didn't just write about bears. They also penned How to Teach Your Children About Sex.</fact>
    <fact>Not a single witch was burned at the stake after being convicted in the Salem witch trials. (Most were hanged.)</fact>
    <fact>The Beach Boys were the founders of surf rock; however, only Dennis Wilson knew how to surf. He died of drowning in 1983.</fact>
    <fact>Gadsby is a 1939 novel by Ernest Vincent Wright with over 50,000 words, and not a single word contains the letter "E."</fact>
    <fact>Something described as "cordiform" is heart-shaped.</fact>
    <fact>Mustard’s name is a contraction of the Latin mustum ardens, meaning “burning wine.”</fact>
    <fact>In 1998, a Georgia student was suspended for wearing a Pepsi shirt to "Coke in Education Day."</fact>
    <fact>On the 2001 New Zealand census, 53,715 people listed their religion as “Jedi.”</fact>
    <fact>Big Ben doesn’t refer to a clock; it's actually the name for the bell inside that famous clock tower.</fact>
    <fact>The name for "piggy banks" comes from the use of family money jars in the Middle Ages made from a type of clay called pygg.</fact>
    <fact>Outside North and South America, the only alligators found in the wild are in China.</fact>
    <fact>Will Smith turned down the role of Neo in The Matrix. Instead he starred in Wild Wild West.</fact>
    <fact>Ringworm is not caused by a worm but by a parasitic fungus.</fact>
    <fact>About five percent of the entire U.S. potato crop goes to make McDonald’s French fries.</fact>
    <fact>When cranberries are ripe, they bounce like a rubber ball.</fact>
    <fact>The first single issued by singer-songwriter Cat Stevens was titled "I Love My Dog."</fact>
    <fact>At the Wife Carrying World Championships in Finland, first prize is the wife’s weight in beer.</fact>
    <fact>ABBA had to negotiate the rights to their name with a canned fish company.</fact>
    <fact>The lowest batting average to win a batting title was .301 by Carl Yastrzemski in 1968.</fact>
    <fact>While they were in the White House, John and Abigail Adams had dogs named Satan and Juno.</fact>
    <fact>Wendy's founder, Dave Thomas, used to work for Kentucky Fried Chicken.</fact>
    <fact>One of the first known contraceptives was crocodile dung, used by Egyptians.</fact>
    <fact>Gureng-gureng, Gabi-Gabi, Waga-Waga, Wemba-Wemba, and Yitha-Yitha are all names of native Australian languages.</fact>
    <fact>Mushroom clouds can be created by any huge explosion; they aren't specific to atomic blasts.</fact>
    <fact>The tune to "The Star-Spangled Banner" originates to the tune of an old drinking song,"The Anacreontic Song."</fact>
    <fact>The U.S. Marine Corps is actually older than the United States itself, having been founded in 1775.</fact>
    <fact>Just as some people talk in their sleep, sign language speakers have been known to sign in their sleep.</fact>
    <fact>Depending on the time of year, the Earth's distance from the Sun can vary more than 3 million miles.</fact>
    <fact>Presidential retreat Camp David is named after Dwight Eisenhower’s grandson.</fact>
    <fact>The national animal of Scotland is the unicorn.</fact>
    <fact>The poinsettia's red petals are actually leaves.</fact>
    <fact>During WWII, Tootsie Rolls were added to soldiers' rations thanks to their durability in all weather conditions.</fact>
    <fact>Johnny Carson’s first three wives were named, in order, Joan, Joanne, and Joanna. (His first wife went by "Jody.")</fact>
    <fact>The first man to appear on the cover of Playboy was the actor Peter Sellers.</fact>
    <fact>Television lost about 20 percent of its advertising revenue immediately after tobacco ads were banned in 1971.</fact>
    <fact>The little plastic bit on the end of your shoelace is called an aglet.    </fact>
    <fact>Lincoln Logs were invented by Frank Lloyd Wright’s son.</fact>
    <fact>Leonard Maltin's complete review of the 1948 film Isn't It Romantic?: "No."</fact>
    <fact>Only one breed of dog is mentioned by name in the Bible: the Greyhound. (Proverbs 30:29-31, King James Version).</fact>
    <fact>The Iron Man edition of Mr. Potato Head is named Tony Starch.</fact>
    <fact>A sequel called Beetlejuice Goes Hawaiian was written but never produced.</fact>
    <fact>The North Magnetic Pole, once located over Canada, is now in the Arctic Ocean and is slowly moving towards Russia.</fact>
    <fact>New Mexico State’s first graduating class in 1893 had only one student— and he was shot and killed before graduation.</fact>
    <fact>At Fatburger, you can order a "Hypocrite" — a veggie burger topped with crispy strips of bacon.</fact>
    <fact>The hyoid bone is the only bone in the human body not connected to another bone.</fact>
    <fact>Pringles chips are named after a street in Finneytown, a tiny Cincinnati suburb.</fact>
    <fact>The word "tycoon" is based on taikun, a title used by Japanese Shoguns.</fact>
    <fact>Neil Armstrong stepped onto the moon with his left foot first.</fact>
    <fact>Emperor Hirohito was more than a political power; he was also well respected in the field of marine biology.</fact>
    <fact>The 1984 film Red Dawn was the first to garner a PG-13 rating.</fact>
    <fact>Because he had bad eyesight, Harry Truman memorized the letters on the eye chart to get into the Army.</fact>
    <fact>The first U.S. dog guide was a German Shepherd named “Buddy.” He was presented to Morris Frank in 1927.</fact>
    <fact>Clarence Birdseye founded his frozen food empire with $7. It bought him an electric fan, cakes of ice, and buckets of brine.</fact>
    <fact>Liquid measurements are different in Britain than in the United States: A fluid ounce is smaller, while pints, quarts, and gallons are larger.</fact>
    <fact>The Spanish omelette was actually invented in Spain, but over there it’s eaten as lunch or dinner and is often served cold.</fact>
    <fact>The poinsettia, the red-and-green flower commonly seen in Christmas arrangements, isn't snow-friendly; it's native to sunny Mexico.</fact>
    <fact>Why don't stores sell mouse-flavored cat food? It's a matter of marketing; tuna, chicken and liver flavors sound much more palatable to consumers.</fact>
    <fact>Scientists believe heavy UV radiation has turned all the American flags on the moon white.</fact>
    <fact>There is a Librarian of Congress.</fact>
    <fact>Peladophobia is the fear of bald people.</fact>
    <fact>G-rated family films earn more money than any other rated films; however, only 4% of Hollywood's output is G-rated.</fact>
    <fact>The dishwasher was invented by Josephine Cochrane— a socialite who was tired of servants breaking her expensive dishes.</fact>
    <fact>Jimi Hendrix actually opened for the Monkees.</fact>
    <fact>In 1835, John Wilkes Booth’s father Junius threatened to kill President Andrew Jackson.</fact>
    <fact>The first president to earn a PhD was Woodrow Wilson.</fact>
    <fact>Yawning is so contagious that it can spread to dogs and monkeys.</fact>
    <fact>Ohio is the only state without a traditional state flag. It has a pennant.</fact>
    <fact>The term "paparazzi" comes from Paparazzo, a fictional freelance photographer in the 1960 Fellini film La Dolce Vita.</fact>
    <fact>Fish can taste with their fins and tail as well as their mouth.</fact>
    <fact>You know the famous Warhol portrait of Marilyn Monroe? It's based on a publicity still shot by Gene Korman for her 1953 movie Niagara.</fact>
    <fact>Geologists believe that about half the unmined gold in the world is in South Africa.</fact>
    <fact>About half the geysers on Earth are located in Yellowstone National Park.</fact>
    <fact>Woodrow Wilson's first name was Thomas. Woodrow was actually his middle name.</fact>
    <fact>There really was a Captain Morgan. He was a Welsh pirate who later became the lieutenant governor of Jamaica.</fact>
    <fact>Nearly $40 billion in U.S. coins are currently in circulation.</fact>
    <fact>George de Mestral, the inventor of Velcro, also received a patent for a toy plane at age 12.</fact>
    <fact>Since 1950, Georgia has flown four different state flags. The design was changed in 1956, in 2001, and again in 2003.</fact>
    <fact>The world famous State Hermitage Museum began as the personal art collection of Catherine the Great.</fact>
    <fact>Don't tease the jaws of a Venus flytrap. Each jaw can only close a few times before the plant dies.</fact>
    <fact>Why did the FBI call Ted Kaczynski "The Unabomber"? His early mail bombs were sent to universities (UN) and airlines (A).</fact>
    <fact>A person of average size and weight burns about 60 to 70 calories each hour just by sitting and watching television.</fact>
    <fact>A newborn giant panda is about the size of a stick of butter.</fact>
    <fact>Will Smith's hit song "Gettin' Jiggy Wit It" was actually co-written by hip hop artist Nas.</fact>
    <fact>The popular dice game known as Yahtzee was created by a Canadian couple who played it aboard their yacht — hence the name.</fact>
    <fact>In 2003, Dennis Gross set the unofficial record for Most Peeps Eaten in 30 Minutes. He polished off 102 Peeps.</fact>
    <fact>William Howard Taft was not only the heaviest U.S. president, but also the last to sport facial hair.</fact>
    <fact>So-called white chocolate isn't chocolate in the technical sense — it is comprised of cocoa butter, sugar, and milk, but no actual chocolate.</fact>
    <fact>The original name for the starship in Star Trek was "Yorktown," not "Enterprise".</fact>
    <fact>The Procrastinators' Club of America newsletter is called “Last Month’s Newsletter.”</fact>
    <fact>Giant squids have been known to feast on baby whales.</fact>
    <fact>Since 1932, only Jimmy Carter and George H.W. Bush have failed in their bids for re-election to a second presidential term.</fact>
    <fact>Even Fidel Castro lashed out against New Coke, calling it "a sign of American capitalist decadence."</fact>
    <fact>Dolph Lundgren, who played Ivan Drago in Rocky IV, has a master's degree in chemical engineering. He's also Swedish.</fact>
    <fact>The first known chain letter appeared in 1888 soliciting for dimes for the poor in Tennessee and promising God’s blessing in return.</fact>
    <fact>In the 1980s, a product called Vision-Dieter glasses promised to curb your appetite by making food look unappealing</fact>
    <fact>Director John Landis includes the phrase "See you next Wednesday" in most of his films. It was the title of a script he wrote as a teen.</fact>
    <fact>Chinese judges in the 15th century used darkened lenses (sunglasses) to hide their facial expressions in court.</fact>
    <fact>Unlike a traditional toxin, viper venom functions by preventing the blood from clotting so that the victims bleed to death.</fact>
    <fact>A shampoo containing real beer was marketed in the 1970s under the brand name Body On Tap.</fact>
    <fact>The Harlem Globetotters were originally a Chicago based team (1927). They did not play a game in Harlem until the 1960s.</fact>
    <fact>Janis Joplin left $2,500 in her will for her friends to "have a ball after I’m gone."</fact>
    <fact>In the 1980s, a product called Vision-Dieter glasses promised to curb your appetite by making food look unappealing.</fact>
    <fact>King Louis XIV was so afraid of weapons that he ruled all pointed knives at dinner tables illegal.</fact>
    <fact>Construction of the Pentagon began on September 11th, 1941.</fact>
    <fact>Seashell fossils have been found high in the Himalayan mountains, suggesting that the land was once underwater.</fact>
    <fact>In France, the Ashton Kutcher/Natalie Portman movie No Strings Attached was called Sex Friends.</fact>
    <fact>The last state to ban eugenics-based castration was Oregon in 1983. The last castration took place in 1978.</fact>
    <fact>Teddy Roosevelt is the youngest man to become President (age 42) while John F Kennedy is the youngest man to be elected President (age 43).</fact>
    <fact>Former First Brother Roger Clinton had his share of embarrassing incidents, including an appearance in the film Bio-Dome.</fact>
    <fact>February is the only month that can pass without a single Full Moon.</fact>
    <fact>PETA once asked the Pet Shop Boys to consider changing their name to Rescue Shelter Boys.</fact>
    <fact>In 1998 Miss Piggy released her own perfume, "Moi." Kermit had previously debuted a cologne called "Amphibia."</fact>
    <fact>James Dolan, CEO of Cablevision and owner of the New York Knicks and the New York Rangers, also fronts the blues band JD and the Straight Shot.</fact>
    <fact>The world's largest rodent is the capybara.</fact>
    <fact>The aorta of a blue whale is large enough for a human to crawl through.</fact>
    <fact>Aardvark is Afrikaans for earth pig</fact>
    <fact>It doesn't matter how fresh-picked they are, coffee beans are actually tasteless until they're roasted.</fact>
    <fact>The Latin version of Winnie the Pooh (Winnie ille Pu) made the New York Times bestseller list in 1960.</fact>
    <fact>Teddy Roosevelt's first wife and mother died on the same day in the same house. The day was Valentine's Day of 1884.</fact>
    <fact>The scale that classifies hurricanes into Categories 1-5 is called the Saffir-Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale.</fact>
    <fact>Gasoline was once sold in small bottles as a cure for lice.</fact>
    <fact>The dots on dice and dominoes are called 'pips.'</fact>
    <fact>The Salem Witch trials did not start in Salem, MA. They started in Salem Village, now known as Danvers.</fact>
    <fact>The Pony Express only lasted a single year before the transcontinental telegraph made the route obsolete.</fact>
    <fact>In addition to writing for Clarissa Explains It All, Hunger Games author Suzanne Collins also penned several episodes of Wow! Wow! Wubbzy!</fact>
    <fact>The first NHL team to use artificial ice wasn't a warm-weather franchise; it was the Toronto Arenas (now the Maple Leafs) in 1917.</fact>
    <fact>Duct tape was developed in 1942 for use by the U.S. Army as a waterproof sealing tape for ammunition boxes.</fact>
    <fact>Oregon is the only state to have a different design on each side of its flag.</fact>
    <fact>In a 2004 episode of Sesame Street, Cookie Monster said that before he started eating cookies, his name was Sid.</fact>
    <fact>The Vatican Bank is the world’s only bank that allows ATM users to perform transactions in Latin.</fact>
    <fact>7-Up was originally called "Bib-Label Lithiated Lemon-Lime Soda."</fact>
    <fact>Only a few species of piranha are carnivorous; most eat plant matter or insects.</fact>
    <fact>Wilford Brimley was Howard Hughes' bodyguard.</fact>
    <fact>The spitting spider doesn't wait for insects to get caught in its web; it spits out sticky strings that capture the prey where it stands.</fact>
    <fact>It’s not widely publicized, but Mr. Clean has a first name: “Veritably.”</fact>
    <fact>Rogaine and Viagra were discovered by testing potential blood pressure medicines.</fact>
    <fact>The only father-daughter collaboration to hit number one on the Billboard pop chart was “Something Stupid” by Frank and Nancy Sinatra in 1967</fact>
    <fact>In 2010, a sex pheromone found in male mouse urine was named "darcin" for Jane Austen’s Mr. Darcy.</fact>
    <fact>There is a word that rhymes with orange! It’s sporange: a rare alternative form of sporangium, a botany term that means "spore case."</fact>
    <fact>Cashews are actually a fleshy fruit. The nut that we eat is the seed that grows on the outside of the fruit.</fact>
    <fact>Japan is commonly thought of as a tiny island nation, but it's actually about the size of California. In fact, it's larger than many European countries.</fact>
    <fact>The Pentagon has twice the number of toilets needed due to being built before desegregation.</fact>
    <fact>Descartes was attracted to cross-eyed women.</fact>
    <fact>Homosexuality was still classified as an illness in Sweden in 1979. Swedes protested by calling in sick to work, claiming they felt gay.</fact>
    <fact>Chad and Barbie Soper of Rockford, Michigan, have three kids. They were born on 08/08/08, 09/09/09, and 10/10/10.</fact>
    <fact>How did Curious George get to America? In the original book, George was captured in Africa by The Man With the Yellow Hat— by means of his yellow hat.</fact>
    <fact>In 1759, St. James's Gate Brewery (where they brew Guinness) was leased for to Arthur Guinness for 9,000 years for 45 pounds per year.</fact>
    <fact>A trip around the bases on a baseball diamond is 20 yards longer than a goal-line-to-goal line run on a football field.</fact>
    <fact>The bat is the only mammal that can fly. Flying squirrels can only glide (fall slowly).</fact>
    <fact>Pepsi-Cola was originally called “Brad’s Drink.”</fact>
    <fact>The Arkansas School for the Deaf's nickname is the Leopards.</fact>
    <fact>Charles Curtis, Herbert Hoover's Vice President, was a Kaw Indian. As of today, he achieved the highest elected office of any Native American.</fact>
    <fact>Cheerleading was initially an all-male sport. Females were only added to the equation when smaller, lighter bodies were needed for "flying."</fact>
    <fact>The country with the most feral camels is Australia.</fact>
    <fact>Billiards was once a lawn game played outdoors, which is why today’s pool tables have a green felt cover.</fact>
    <fact>111,111,111 x 111,111,111 = 12,345,678,987,654,321</fact>
    <fact>The "S" in Harry S. Truman didn't stand for anything; Truman had a middle initial but no middle name.</fact>
    <fact>The nutrition info on Swedish Chef's Cröonchy Stars says the cereal contains no shoe trees, venetian blinds, or pachyderms.</fact>
    <fact>Sweaters were originally knitted from unwashed wool because the natural oils made the garment more waterproof.</fact>
    <fact>Tug of War was an Olympic event from 1900 to 1920.</fact>
    <fact>With a nurse and a calligrapher, Saddam Hussein had a copy of the Koran written using his own blood.</fact>
    <fact>The first video uploaded to YouTube featured co-founder Jawed Karim discussing elephants at the San Diego Zoo.</fact>
    <fact>Because of the angle at which its esophagus enters its stomach, the horse is physically unable to vomit.</fact>
    <fact>Human arms have 32 bones each, while human legs only have 30.</fact>
    <fact>When Canada's Northwest Territories considered renaming itself in the 1990s, one possibility was "Bob."</fact>
    <fact>The Rockola jukebox wasn't named for rock music, but rather for its inventor, David Rockola.</fact>
    <fact>The world's largest exporter of beef isn't the United States; it's Australia.</fact>
    <fact>While an Oscar is of unnamed value to someone who wins (or loses) one, the actual trophy is estimated to be worth about $150.</fact>
    <fact>Other than tap water, coffee is the favorite beverage among adult Canadians, who reportedly consume an average of 2.6 cups per day.</fact>
    <fact>If your doctor is going to perform an auscultation on you, don't worry; he or she will just be using his stethoscope.</fact>
    <fact>The familiar piano tune we know as “Chopsticks” was written by a 16-year-old girl in 1877 and was published as “The Celebrated Chop Waltz.”</fact>
    <fact>Wilt Chamberlain was the only NBA center to lead the league in assists.</fact>
    <fact>Brenda Lee was only 13 when she recorded “Rockin’ Around the Christmas Tree.”</fact>
    <fact>Frank Sinatra was the producer's first choice to play the role of Harry Callahan in Dirty Harry.</fact>
    <fact>When dragonflies mate, their tails form a heart.</fact>
    <fact>There is actually more copper in a U.S. nickel than there is in a penny.</fact>
    <fact>Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, who created the literary character Sherlock Holmes, helped popularize skiing in Switzerland.</fact>
    <fact>Researchers believe that herring communicate with one another in a way humans would find repulsive: passing gas.</fact>
    <fact>Russia's Sergei Avdeyev has traveled further than any other human in history, completing nearly 12,000 orbits of the Earth as a cosmonaut.</fact>
    <fact>The dot of the letter "i" is called a tittle.</fact>
    <fact>The flashes of colored light you see when you rub your eyes are called "phosphenes."</fact>
    <fact>At points in the 1990s, 50% of all CDs being produced worldwide were for AOL.</fact>
    <fact>Both James Madison and Alexander Hamilton helped George Washington write his famous Farewell Address.</fact>
    <fact>Jack London's Call of the Wild reportedly earned the author a single, flat-fee payment of only $2,000.</fact>
    <fact>After a 2011 vote, Toyota announced that the official plural of Prius was Prii.</fact>
    <fact>Exterior color preference varies with the type of vehicle: white is most common for trucks, black for luxury cars, and silver for other cars.</fact>
    <fact>Taco Bell is named for its founder, Glen Bell.</fact>
    <fact>Cleopatra had a special lipstick made for her, consisting of crushed ants and deep red carmine beetles.</fact>
    <fact>Dog tags are always worn in pairs in case of the unthinkable; one tag remains with the body, and the other is sent to Mortuary Affairs.</fact>
    <fact>Lieutenant Theo Kojak sucked on lollipops because the actor who played him, Telly Savalas, was trying to quit smoking.</fact>
    <fact>Through the first half of the 20th century, only one winner of the Oscar for Best Picture was filmed in color: Gone with the Wind.</fact>
    <fact>Nixon was speaking at Disney World when he famously declared, "I am not a crook."</fact>
    <fact>Canada has more lakes than all the other countries combined.</fact>
    <fact>The glue used on Israeli postage stamps is kosher.</fact>
    <fact>Madonna's last name is Ciccone.</fact>
    <fact>Although estimates vary, humans blink their eyes around five million times each year.</fact>
    <fact>Composer Erik Satie would only eat white foods.</fact>
    <fact>12+1 = 11+2, and "twelve plus one" is an anagram of "eleven plus two."</fact>
    <fact>Sea otters hold hands when they sleep so they don't drift apart.</fact>
    <fact>The 50 tallest mountains on Earth are all located in Asia.</fact>
    <fact>In what countries are people most likely to help a stranger? In a 2010 survey, Liberia and Sierra Leone were #1 and #2.</fact>
    <fact>Hawaii is the most geographically isolated land mass in the world.</fact>
    <fact>Vodka was used as an ingredient in early European formulations of gunpowder.</fact>
    <fact>Bone cells are constantly renewed, so every ten years you have a "new" skeleton.</fact>
    <fact>Nearly 30% of Dalmatian dogs are born with complete or partial hearing loss.</fact>
    <fact>The infinity sign is properly known as a "lemniscate."</fact>
    <fact>The Eiffel Tower in Paris, France, leans slightly toward the shade on sunny days!</fact>
    <fact>John Adams drank a tankard of hard cider each day and had the occasional beer for breakfast.</fact>
    <fact>To prepare for his Cheers audition, Ted Danson said he spent two weeks attending a bartending school in Burbank.</fact>
    <fact>Both Madonna and Celine Dion are cousins of Prince Charles' wife, Camilla.</fact>
    <fact>More people watched Elvis's Aloha from Hawaii than the landing on the Moon.</fact>
    <fact>Valium is an all-natural chemical. In fact, trace amounts can be found in wheat and potatoes.</fact>
    <fact>In 2000, a New Jersey man admitted he'd opened 2,417 accounts using 16 PO boxes to fleece Columbia House and BMG out of 26,554 CDs.</fact>
    <fact>Both the flesh and the pit of avocados are toxic to most species of birds.</fact>
    <fact>Grover Cleveland is the only U.S. President to serve two non-consecutive terms. He was the 22nd AND the 24th U.S. President.</fact>
    <fact>How much do we really love the Golden Arches? About five percent of the entire U.S. potato crop goes to make McDonald’s French fries.</fact>
    <fact>The white part of an egg is called the "albumen."</fact>
    <fact>Jim Cummings, the voice of Winnie the Pooh, calls sick kids in hospitals and chats with them in character.</fact>
    <fact>Johnny Cash’s “A Boy Named Sue” was written by Shel Silverstein.</fact>
    <fact>BVD stands for the last names of the underwear company's three founders: Bradley, Voorhees, and Day.</fact>
    <fact>When referring to China, make sure to say the People's Republic of China. Leave off "People's" and you're talking about Taiwan.</fact>
    <fact>About one in every 2 million lobsters is born with a rare genetic defect that turns it blue.</fact>
    <fact>According to legend, Honore de Balzac drank 50 cups of coffee a day to fuel his writing.</fact>
    <fact>Thomas Jefferson wrote parts of the Declaration of Independence in a Philadelphia tavern.</fact>
    <fact>Only 17 existing paintings are attributed to famed artist Leonardo da Vinci.</fact>
    <fact>The inventors of Bubble Wrap were originally trying to make plastic wallpaper.</fact>
</facts>